老爸老妈的罗漫史\n第一季 第七集
Drama Name:how i met your mother\nSeason 1 Episode 07
孩子们, 在我遇见你们妈妈前
Kids,before I met your mother,
当我仍然在寻找我的另一半时
when I was still out there searching,
我学到了一点
I learned something valuable.
那就是爱情不是科学
That love is not a science.
哇, 这真是个伟大的故事, 爸
Wow,that was great story,dad.
我们要去看电视了
We're going to go watch TV.
你们看, 有时候
You see,sometimes in life
你必须得接受
you just have to accept that
世界上某些事情是解释不了的
certain things can't be explained.
而且会让人感到震惊
And that's kind of scary.
噢, 天那
Oh,my god.
我知道, 我还在害怕
I know,I'm still shaking.
怎么...? 开个玩笑, 我感冒了
What the...? Joke's on you,I have a cold.
你们还好吧?
Are you guys okay?
又转了一圈, 冲着我和Lily来了!
Another round,and back it up for me and lily!
- 怎么啦?\n- 我们看见公寓里有些东西
-What happened?\n- We saw something up in the apartment.
很糟糕的东西
Something bad.
我不知道怎么了
I don't know what it is,
- 但是玛格丽塔让我兴奋（一种鸡尾酒）\n- 噢, muchos sexy.
-but margaritas make me sexy.\n- Oh,muchos sexy.
Yo quiero, Marshall\nYo quiero,marshall.
噢, 天那
Oh,my god.
那是什么? 绝对是你见过的最疯狂
what was it? Only the craziest,
最难看的老鼠
meanest looking mouse you've ever seen.
老鼠? 亲爱的, 那不是老鼠
Mouse? Sweetie,that wasn't a mouse.
是只巨型蟑螂
That was a huge cockroach.
宝贝, 那是只老鼠
Baby,it was a mouse.
它有须的
It had whiskers.
但那些东西是从它脑袋上冒出来的
But those things coming out of its head,
那些是触角
those were antennae.
Marshall被只蟑螂吓跑了
Marshall ran away from a cockroach.
那是老鼠
It was a mouse.
噢, 好, 抱歉, 兄弟\n你真是个男人
Oh,yeah,sorry,my bad.You're a man.
噢, 我的报道开始了\nTed, 注意了
Oh,my story is on.Ted,pay attention.
Carl, 开电视
Carl,turn it up.
在我身边的是Ellen Pierce
I'm here with ellen pierce,
纽约尖端配偶师
new york's premiere matchmaker.
Ellen, 你的公司, 恋爱配对中心
Ellen,your company,love solutions,
号称达到100%的成功率
boasts 100% success rate.
- 有什么秘诀吗?\n- 科学
-What's your secret?\n-Science.
生活中的每件事
Everything in life
都能被分解为数字, 甚至于爱情
can be broken down to ones and zeros,even love.
我所要做的就是把这些不定因素
All I have to do is input the variables,
放入系统中, 然后就可以宣布
run the algorithm,and presto manifesto,
你有一个灵魂伴侣啦\n这完全是可行的!
you have a soul mate,and it works!
只要去问问我促成的\n那些夫妻就知道了
Just ask all of my happy couples.
这只是比较有吸引力的一部分
And these are just the attractive ones.
浴室里还有更多照片
I have more photos in the bathroom.
恋爱配对中心, Ellen Pierce
Love solutions,ellen pierce.
纽约失恋者们的一线希望
A beacon of hope for new york city's lovelorn.
Robin Scherbotsky...\nRobin scherbotsky... was that
最后面那个女的真的是客户吗?
chick at the end really a client?
- 嗯\n- 我们要去那
Yes. We're signing up.
- 什么?\n- Ted, 这些女人绝望而且性感
What? Ted,these chicks are desperate and hot.
这是完美的鸡尾酒
That's a perfect cocktail.
摇匀, 然后上床
Shake well,then sleep with.
我不会去找配偶师
I'm not going to a matchmaker.
这象放弃希望
That's like giving up.
这是找只猫过晚年的男性版
It's the man version of getting a cat.
不, 那不是蟑螂
No,it wasn't a cockroach.
它有皮毛, 只有哺乳动物有皮毛
It had fur,and only mammals have fur.
那就是只蟑螂
It was a cockroach.
拜托, Lily
Come on,lily,
除非它是只披着
the only way that
死老鼠皮的蟑螂
that was a cockroach
才有可能
is if it was wearing the skin of a mouse it just killed.
噢, 天那
Oh,my god.
拜托
come on.
Ted! 快点!\n你得帮帮我
ted! hurry! You've got to help me.
我的船要沉啦!
My boat is sinking!
- 什么?\n- 我的船要沉啦!
-What?\n- My boat is sinking!
你有船吗?
You have a boat?
是啊, 我去年在警察拍卖会上买的
Yes,I bought a boat last year at a police auction.
我刚接到了一个在码头的家伙的电话
I just got a call from a guy down at the marina
它向右倾斜了45度角
that it's leaning starboard at a 45 degree angle.
如果我现在不去那的话
If I don't get down there right now,
船就要翻啦 快走吧!
it's going to capsize. Now come on!
- 你的船沉了 这真不错\n- 拜托, Ted
-Your boat is sinking. That was good.\n- Come on,ted.
这是个难以另人置信的机会
This is an incredible opportunity.
我们将碰到灵魂伴侣
We'll meet our soul mates,
上了她们然后消失
nail 'em and never call 'em again.
好了吗, 先生们?
All finished,gentlemen?
恭喜你们
Congratulations.
你们刚刚迈出了第一步
You have just taken your very first step.
天那, 谢谢你, Ellen
Gosh,thanks,ellen.
我很相信这能帮到我
I sure hope this works.
我已经厌倦了单身生活
I'm so done with the single life--
所有的这些游戏, 无意义的性爱
all the games,the meaningless sex.
你应该得到更多
You deserve more.
确实如此, Ellen
That is so true,ellen.
我真觉得我应该停止单身
I really think I'm ready to stop being a me,
开始2个人的生活
and start being a we.
嘿
Hey,is there any way
我能说我喜欢拥抱吗?
I can let it be known that I love cuddling?
啊, 当然可以\n这太... 噢
Ah,of course you can.That is so... oh.
Ted在这我不好意思说出口
Kind of hard to talk about with ted here,
但我想要的人是不会
but I just want someone who's not afraid
在夜晚害怕搂住我...
to hold me at night...
当我哭泣的时候
When the tears come.
Ellen, 你能帮我找到这样一个她吗?
Ellen,can you help me find her?
- 滚出去\n- 怎么?
-Get out.\n-What?
每天都会有15个象你这样的家伙
I get 15 guys like you every week.
想找容易上手的女人
Jerks who just want to meet vulnerable women,
上了她然后消失掉
nail 'em and never call 'em again.
噢, 天那, 有人会这样吗?
Oh,my god,people do that?
你想用什么方式出去
Do you want to do this
舒服点的还是痛苦点的?
the easy way or the hard way?
比较痛苦的是什么?
What's the hard way?
保安把我给丢出去吗?
Security roughs me up and tosses me out?
不, 那是比较舒服的方式
No,that's the easy way.
比较痛苦的是
The hard way is that
我亲自把你给踢出去
I stomp the crap out of you myself.
好吧, Ted, 我们走
Okay,ted,let's go.
不是你 你留下来
Not you. You stay.
你很讨人喜欢，你是个设计师
You're cute. You're an architect.
不错的职业
Good career,
你也没有在简历上用很明显的假名
and you didn't use an obvious alias on your application,
比方说你的朋友Jack Package
like your friend jack package.
它的发音应该是 pa-codge
It's pronounced pa-codge.
滚出去! 你, 我能帮你
Get out of here! You,I can work with.
给我3天时间
You give me three days,and I will find
我会找出你的伴侣
the woman you will marry.
呃, 不用了谢了
Uh,no thanks.
我不需要一个算术系统\n来帮我找女朋友
I don't need an algorithm to meet women.
这里是纽约
It's new york city,
你知道 大海里有很多鱼
you know-- plenty of fish in the sea.
大海里有很多鱼
Plenty of fish in the sea.
嗯, 纽约有九百万人口
Yes,there's nine million people in new york,
四百五十万女人
4.5 million women.
当然
Of course,you want to meet
你想要的是跟你年龄差不多的
somebody roughly your own age.
我们就假设, 加减五年内
Let's say,plus,minus,five years.
所以根据我们最新的数据
So if we take into account the most recent census data,
只剩下四十八万两千人合乎标准了
that leaves us with 482,000.
但是, 呃, 等等...
But,uh,wait...
其中48%已经有主了
48% of those are already in relationships,
再排除掉一半
and then you have to eliminate half
还要考虑智商, 幽默感
for intelligence,sense of humor
和你知趣相投的\n然后再去掉
and compatibility,and then you have to take out
你的前女朋友和亲戚
the ex-girlfriends and the relatives,
最后, 噢, 别忘了同性恋
and,oh,we can't forget those lesbians.
剩下的只有八个啦
And then that leaves us with eight women.
这不可能\n八个? 真的吗? 就八个?
That can't be right. Eight? Really? Eight?
八条鱼在这片大海洋里, Ted
There are eight fish in that big blue ocean,ted.
如果你有绝对的自信可以不用我的帮助
And if you feel confident that you could reel one
钓一条上船, 门就在那边
in to your boat without me,there's the door.
你这可以刷卡吗?
Do you take credit cards?
好吧, 它又来了
Okay,it's back.
我们这次看仔细了
And this time we got a good look.
嘿, 我认真的, 你得停止这样
Hey,seriously,you have to stop doing that.
它长的更大了 它喂的很饱
It's bigger now. It's been feeding.
我们在楼上看电视
We were just upstairs watching TV.
噢, 天那
Oh,gosh.
好吧,我们来干吧
okay,let's do this.
shh,shh,shh（尖叫声）
shh,shh,shh.
没事了 都过去了\n噢, 天那!
It's okay. It's over. Oh,god!
那么你们看清楚那东西啦?
So did you get a good look at it?
是啊 它有六只脚
Yeah. It has six legs,
有坚硬的甲壳, 就象蟑螂
a hard exoskeleton,like a roach.
但是它有老鼠的特点
But it had mouse-like characteristics.
灰色的皮毛和尾巴
Grey-brown tufts of fur,a tail.
那到底是什么, 蟑螂还是老鼠?
So which is it,a cockroach or a mouse?
- 它只蟑螂鼠\n- 什么?
-It's a cock-a-mouse.\n-What?
它是两种的综合变异体
It's some sort of mutant combination of the two.
就象一只老鼠和蟑螂
It's as if a cockroach and a mouse,
你们知道...
you know...
地面上有这种10条腿的混合物种吗?
did the horizontal,ten-legged,interspecies cha-cha?
这不可能
That's impossible.
不会发生这种事
That simply can't happen.
-噢, 但是可以\n-它确实发生了
Oh,but it can. And it has.
而且很生气
And it's pissed.
伙计, 没什么事吧?
Dude,is everything okay?
你们的门没关
You left the front door open.
是没时间关
There was no time.
嗯, 恋爱配对中心?
So,love solutions?
你碰到你的爱人了?
Did you meet the love of your life?
她说只要三天
She said it'd take three days.
现在已经五天了
It's been five days.
我应该担心吗?
Should I be worried?
噢, 别当回事
Oh,just play it cool.
别太担心
Don't ted out about it.
你刚刚把我的名字当动词用吗?
Did you just use my name as a verb?
噢, 嗯\n我们在你背后一直那样
Oh,yeah. We do that behind your back.
"Ted out" 表示想太多
"Ted out," to overthink.
还有"Ted up"
Also see "ted up."
"Ted up"表示想太多
"Ted up"-- to overthink something
不好的结果
with disastrous results.
列如: Billy 想太多不好的结果
Sample sentence: Billy tedded up
当他... 好了
when he tried... okay,
我知道了 别担心
I get it. Don't worry.
我不会担心太多
I'm not going to ted anything up. Or out.
我得多给她点时间
I should give it a few more days.
嗨, Ellen 记得我吗?
Hi,ellen. Remember me?
我是Ted
I'm ted.
Ted, 嗨\n我, 呃, 本来想打电话给你
Ted,hi. I,uh,meant to call you.
电脑仍然在处理数据
The computer is still crunching the numbers.
象勤劳的蜜蜂, 可爱的小电脑
Busy as a bee,that little computer.
你说只要三天
You said it was going to be three days.
- 我有吗? 嗯\n- 三天? 真的吗? 是啊
-Did I? Hmm. \n-Three days? Really? Yeah,
当有人说
and when someone says
你将在三天内碰到你的完美女人
you're going to meet the perfect woman in three days,
你会考虑把这加到约会表里
you kind of put that in your date book,
那么...\n我该怎么说呢?
so... how do I say this?
这事变的很艰难
This is going to be really hard.
Ted... 我找不到
Ted... there are absolutely
任何一个女人给你
no women out there for you.
唷, 还好, 我熬过这一刻了
Phew,actually,I got through that okay.
找不到一个女人给我？我以为会有八个适合我的
There are no women out there for me?\nI thought you said there were eight.
我知道 理论上应该是
I know. There are supposed to be.
但我不知道她们哪去了
I don't know where they are.
但... 我是个设计师
But... I'm an architect.
你也说我很讨人喜欢
And you said I'm cute.
我是个讨人喜欢的设计师
I'm a cute architect.
你觉得我怎么想?
How do you think I feel?
我有100%的成功率
I have a 100% success rate.
这是我的卖点
That's my hook.
我也许能给你找到某人
I could maybe find somebody for you
如果你是同性恋
if you were gay.
嗯, 我不是
Well,I'm not.
有一点双性恋?
A little bi maybe?
不! 你在和我开玩笑, 是不?
No! You're messing with me,right?
你自己过来看看
Come see for yourself.
我不能给你配对
I can not set you up
除非你融合度有7.0
unless you have a compatibility rating of 7.0
或者再高点
or higher.
-看, 5.4, 4.8, 5.6\n-有个9.6在那
And look,5.4,4.8,5.6. There's a 9.6 right there.
别碰电脑
Don't touch the computer.
对, Sarah O'brien
Yes,sarah o'brien.
我六个月前已经给她找对象了
I fixed her up six months ago.
她应该更合适你
She would have been absolutely perfect for you.
嗯, 你给他找的那家伙怎么样?
Well,what about the guy you set her up with?
他们的融合度是9.6吗?
Is he a 9.6 compatibility rating?
8.5\n8.5. So he sucks.
那他很烂
不, 8.5已经是很不错的程度了
No,8.5 is an extremely good match-up quotient.
噢, 当然, 那很好
Oh,sure,it's good.
- 很不错, 但是9.6?\n- 9.6是超出想象
-It's solid,but a 9.6? \n-9.6 is off the charts,
但是Sarah已经有主了
but sarah is matched up.
Ted, 听着, 我有午餐约会
Ted,look,I have a lunch.
啊, 我保证我们会找到合适的人
Please,i promise we will find you somebody.
别失去希望
Don't lose hope.
每天都会有女人迈入18岁
There are new women turning 18 every day.
这是个新物种 蟑螂鼠
it's a whole new species-- the cock-a-mouse.
土豆大小
And it's the size of a potato.
那, 现在是只蟑螂土豆鼠?
So what,now it's a cock-a-potato-mouse?
别让这听起来很滑稽
Don't make it sound ridiculous.
这是蟑螂鼠
It's a cock-a-mouse.
我的天, 这太让人难以相信了
My god,this is incredible.
我们就是同一种人
We're like the same person.
Sarah O'brien喜欢吃早午餐\n（晚吃的早餐或早吃的午餐）
Sarah o'brien loves brunch,
她想要两个孩子
she wants to have two children.
她最喜欢的歌是
Her guilty pleasure song is
西尔斯与克罗夫二重唱的\n"夏日微风"
"summer breeze" by seals and crofts.
哇, Ted, 听起来\n你是她的完美女人
Wow,ted,sounds like you're her perfect woman.
就象宏伟的海象
And like the majestic seahorse,
而且是雌雄同体
it's hermaphroditic.
很明显整件事情仍是个迷
Obviously the whole thing is shrouded in mystery.
目前为止我们所知道的关于蟑螂鼠
For as much as we know about the cock-a-mouse,
还有很多我们不知道
there's still so much we don't know.
嗯, 我们知道
Well,we know that there's no
没有蟑螂鼠这类的东西
such thing as the cock-a-mouse.
我们不知道的是
What we don't know is what
你们有没抽大麻
you guys have been smoking.
你真的不相信有蟑螂鼠吗?
So you really don't believe in the cock-a-mouse?
嗯, 我相信你们看到的
Well,I believe that you saw
只是很平常的东西
something perfectly normal,
但是在你们脑海里夸大了, 知道吗?
but you've exaggerated it in your mind,you know?
就象尼斯湖水怪
Like the loch ness monster.
如果你说象尼斯湖水怪
If by "like the loch ness monster,"
是指真正出现过而且让人震惊的话
you mean totally exists and is a wesome,
那么我同意, 这就象尼斯湖水怪
then yeah,it's like the loch ness monster.
它的食物不象我们吃的谷类
Its diet is not unlike our own-- grains,
它很喜欢奶酪
cereals-- and it's awfully fond of cheese.
嗯, 这很奇怪
Okay,this is getting weird.
我们的相同点越来越多
The similarities go on and on.
她讨厌煲电话粥\n我也一样
She hates phonies. I totally hate phonies,too.
她是皮肤病专家\n我有皮肤
she's a dermatologist. I have skin.
你想当她男朋友
You want to be her boyfriend.
她已经有男朋友了
She already has a boy friend,
- 这太凑巧了\n- 是啊
-it's uncanny.\n- All right.
但是我去看看她没什么大碍, 不是吗?
But it wouldn't hurt to check her out,right?
面对面看看我的9.6长什么样?
See what my 9.6 looks like in person?
你知道, 做为一个参考
As,you know,a frame of reference.
如果她觉得多11.45%更好
And if she thinks she can do 11.45% better,
我怎么会拒绝呢?
who am i to deny her that?
对啊
That's right.
我用了数学加法
I did the math.
- 嗨\n- 嗨 我是O'brien医生
-Hi.\n-Hi. I'm dr. O'brien.
我是Mosby设计师
I'm architect mosby.
抱歉, 我只是也想说出我的职业
Sorry,I just wanted to say my job,too.
- 嗨, 我是Ted\n- 嗨 你哪里不有问题?
-Hi,I'm ted. \n-Hi. So what are we doing today?
对, 我, 呃, 我背后长了些痔
Right,I,uh,I have a kind of mole on my back.
可能没什么大不了的, 但我是个谨慎的人
It's probably nothing,but I'm a cautious guy.
我也是这种
I'm exactly the same.
Summer breeze makes me feel fine\nSummer breeze makes me feel fine both:
Blowing through the jasmine in my mind\nBlowing through the jasmine in my mind:
抱歉
Sorry about that.
夏日微风是我最喜欢的歌
"Summer breeze" is my guilty pleasure song.
它一直在我脑中回响着
It's been stuck in my head ever since
自从这周... 早午餐的时候听到后
I heard it this weekend... at brunch.
- 我喜欢早午餐\n- 那是最好的
-I love brunch.\n-It's the best.
只要我不用
As long as I don't have to
边吃边讲电话
spend it with a bunch of phonies.
我喜欢你思考的方式, Mosby设计师
I like the way you think,architect mosby.
嘿, 这可能听起来有点奇怪
Hey,this may sound weird,
但有一次我的衬衫掉了
but it'll definitely sound more
听起来更奇怪
weird once my shirt's off.
我现在要问一句
So I'm going to ask you now.
你周六晚愿意和我共进晚餐吗?
Do you want to have dinner with me saturday night?
这很不错
That's very sweet,
但我周六要结婚了
but I'm actually getting married on saturday.
周五晚呢?
Friday night?
哇 你要结婚啦
wow. You're getting married.
- 恭喜\n- 谢谢
-Congratulations.\n-Thank you.
很抱歉我邀你出去
I'm really sorry I asked you out,
象我们间
it just felt like there could be
有些奇怪的关联
this weird connection between us.
我这样来这里是不是太疯狂了?
How crazy am I coming off here?
只有一点
Only a little.
嗯... 如果有百万分之一的机会
Well... if by some million- to-one long shot
你改变主意不结婚了
and I'm not rooting for this-- you wind up not getting married this weekend,
给我打个电话
give me a call.
好的 但是不会那样的
Okay. But it's not likely.
我穿上礼服太棒了
I look damn good in my dress.
我同意
I'm sure you do.
哇, 这真是高难度的陷阱
Wow,that's a pretty sophisticated trap.
你们认为走鹃会进去吗?
You think the roadrunner's going to fall for it?
好了, 我们知道了\n你是怀疑论者
Okay,we get it.You're skeptical.
但Marshall和我, 我们相信
But marshall and I,we're believers.
-我们相信\n-对, 看看周围
We believe. Yeah,look around.
宇宙充满着迷团和未知的东西
The universe is mysterious and awesome.
有百慕达三角, 鬼神, 北美野人
You've got the bermuda triangle,ghosts,bigfoot.
还有烂地图, 破损的房屋
Bad maps,creaky houses,
穿的象猩猩的乡下人
hillbilly in a gorilla suit.
外星人 噢, 拜托\n你得承认外星人
Aliens. Oh,come on,you've got to give me aliens.
巨石柱, 第51区（跟外星事件有关的区域）
Stonehenge,area 51,
到处都有外星人的足迹
there's alien crap all over the place.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
朋友, 你惹到狗熊了\n（麻烦大了）
My friend,you just poked the bear.
我的9.6适合的人 漂亮
So my 9.6-- beautiful,
迷人, 智慧, 而且订婚了
charming,intelligent,engaged.
噢, Ted\n我为你感到难过
Oh,ted. I'm so sorry.
嗯, 这不太可能
Yeah,it was a long shot.
我告诉她如果改变心意
I told her to call me anyway
就给我打电话
if she changes mind.
我也不知道
but I don't know.
哇, 哇, 哇\n我们别想这个了
Whoa,whoa,whoa. Let's not skip over this.
如果今天你有向\n订婚了的女人表达感情
Raise your hand if earlier today
就举起手来
you hit on an engaged woman.
别这样, Lily
Come on,lily.
别怨玩游戏的人, 怨游戏太烂了
Don't hate the player,hate the game.
"1947年7月2日晚
"On the night of july 2,1947,
在新墨西哥州的罗斯威尔
conditions were clear over roswell,
天气很明朗..."\n- 噢, 天
new mexico..."\n-oh,geez.
噢, 嘿, Ted
Oh,hey,ted,there's a message
你有通电话留言
on the machine for you.
- O'brien医生\n- 什么?
-Dr. O'brien.\n-What?
"突然一列..."\n（著名的外星飞碟坠毁事件）
"When suddenly an array of..."
Ted, 嘿, 我是O'brien医生\n关于今天
Ted,hi,this is d o'brien. About today,
听着, 我需要和你谈谈
listen,I really need to talk to you.
回电给我\n我整天都在办公室
Call me. I'll be at the office all day.
医生要见你了
The doctor will see you now.
我该怎么办?
What should I do?
我得去那对吗, 是吗?
I should totally go down there,right?
别去打扰人家
Don't interfere.
某个家伙正期待着
Some guy is expecting to
周六娶这个女人
marry this woman on saturday.
对, 只有8.5适合度的家伙
Yeah,an 8.5 guy.
听着, 如果我要嫁错人
Look,if I was marrying the wrong person
而真命天子就在那
and the right person was out there and knew it,
我会希望他来我办公室
I'd want that person to come down to
告诉我事情到底怎么回事
my dermatology office and tell me so.
在这个故事里
In that scenario,
我没有干涉什么\n我有个快乐的结局
I'm not interfering,I'm a happy ending.
快乐的结局
Happy ending.
听着, 我得去那
Look,I have to go down there.
我不知道
I don't know what's going to
到那会发生什么
happen when I get there,
但我要给自己一次机会
but I've got to give it a shot.
好吧, 一会见
All right,see you later.
追的愉快
Happy hunting.
等等, 你们去哪?
Wait,where are you guys going?
你们不想留下来看蟑螂老鼠吗?
Don't you want to stay and see the cock-a-mouse?
嗯, 我们要去收割庄稼了
Yeah,we're going to go make some crop circles.
- 噢, 天那\n- 捕捉桶落下来了
-oh,my god \n-holy crap buckets.
我们抓到了\n该怎么办?
We got it. What do we do with it?
冷静 我有个计划
Calm down. I have a plan.
我告诉我的朋友Sadip了
I told my friend sadip about it.
他想把这个
He wants to show it to the
拿到哥伦比亚生物中心
columbia biology department.
- 但是得是活的\n- 等等, 不, 不!
-But it has to be alive. \n-Wait,no,no!
他们会在它身上做实验
They'll do lab experiments on it.
这太狠心了
That's so mean.
我们不能直接用棍子打死它吗?
Shouldn't we just beat it to death with a bat?
又见了
Hello again.
我很高兴你过来了
I'm glad you came down.
我也更愿意面对面跟你说
I would prefer to say this to you in person.
继续, Sarah
Go ahead,sarah.
你能告诉我任何事
You can tell me anything.
你患了基底细胞癌（皮肤癌的一种）
You have a basal cell carcinoma.
- 还有别的要说吗?\n- 你的痔
-Anything else?\n- Your mole.
活组织检查报告出来了
The biopsy came back.
并不威胁生命
It's not life-threatening,
但我们还的检查其他的
but we should excise the rest of it.
等等, 你还是要结婚吗?
Wait,then you're still getting married?
当然我要结婚
Of course I'm still getting married.
但是我们适合度是9.6
But we're a 9.6.
- 什么?\n- 好吧
-Excuse me? \n-Okay.
我去了恋爱配对中心
I went to love solutions,
我看了Ellen Pierce的电脑
and I saw on ellen pierce's computer,
我们两个适合度是9.6
that you and I are a 9.6.
你的未婚夫只有8.5
Your fiancé is only an 8.5.
你看了我的档案?
You looked at my file?
我必须看\n你是唯一和我匹配的
I had to. You're my only match.
你一点也不好奇吗?
Aren't you even a little curious?
把你和你未婚夫拉到一起的那个女人
The woman who set you up with your fiancé,
认为我们两个更适合
thinks we're a better match.
我周六就结婚了
I am getting married on saturday.
- Summer breeze...（歌词）
- Ted\n-Summer breeze...\n-ted.
听着, 你不觉得
Look,don't you think
你不觉得就结婚有点冲动吗
you're being a little impulsive marrying
和一个才认识几个月的家伙?
a guy you just met a few months ago?
你不觉得向一个你刚认识的
Don't you think it's a little impulsive for you
已经订婚了的女人
to proposition an engaged woman
求爱有点冲动吗?
you don't even know?
看? 我们都很冲动
See? We're both impulsive.
我们很适合对方
We're perfect for each other.
Ted, 冷静下来
Ted,just calm down.
冷静?! 你是唯一和我适合的
Calm down?! You're my only match.
天, 那里有台电脑
God,there was a computer
八条鱼在大海里
and there were eight fish in a sea
充满着同性恋...
full of lesbians and...
好了, Ted, Ted
okay,ted,ted.
你真的认为, 相信
Do you honestly believe,deep down,
没有人适合你了吗
that there is no one else out there for you
只是因为一台电脑这样说?
just because some computer says so?
我以前不是
I didn't used to.
但是有数学计算, 我很迷惑
But there was math,I got confused.
爱情不是科学
Love isn't a science.
你不能计算感情
You can't calculate a feeling.
当你真正爱上某人
When you fall in love with someone,
8.5分就相当于完美的10分
an 8.5 equals a perfect ten.
你是对的
You're right.
如果这象你说的那样
If this thing is what you say it is,
这将是我职业生涯的巨大转折点
it could be huge for my career.
打起精神, 伙计
Brace yourself,dude.
这将让你大开眼界
This is going to blow your mind hole.
混蛋，你怎么装得这么兴奋
You bastard. I actually got excited about this.
- 什么?\n- 这是空的
-What?\n-It's empty.
等下, 如果它不在这\n表示... Lily
Wait,but if it's not here,that means... lily.
- Robin!\n-Robin!\n-What?
- 怎么了?
噢, 天那 是真的
oh,god. It's real.
不, 不是吗? 做点什么
No,is it? Do something.
你在干什么?
what the hell was that?
你想灌醉它吗?
You trying to get it drunk?
这是我唯一能想到的
It was the only thing I could think of.
Lily! 感谢老天
Lily! Thank god.
Lily, 我爱你
lily,I love you.
Robin, 把窗户打开!
Robin,open up the window!
开窗!
open the window!
啊! 它还能飞
Ah!it can fly.
哇 哇 哇 自由了, 变异怪物
Wow. Wow. Wow. Be free,mutant beast.
我会怀念我们间的战斗
I'll miss this private war of ours.
我佩服你的顽强...
I grew to admire your tenacious...
老天
holy mother of god,
它往这边飞来了!
it's headed this way!
嗨, Ellen
hi,ellen.
我想要回我的钱
I think I want my money back.
我真失败 我全搞砸了
I'm a failure. I'm all washed up.
我什么都试过了, Ted
I tried everything,ted.
我扩大了搜寻参数
I widened the search parameters.
在系统中搜索
I tweaked the program.
昨晚我站在大街上
Last night I stood out on the street
5个小时拿着你的照片
for five hours showing your photo
希望能在行人中找到合适的人
to random pedestrians.
没人愿意
No takers.
尽管那些易装妓女说
Although this transvestite hooker said
他/她愿意半价让你上
he/she would do you for half price
因为你长的象John Cusack
because you kind of look like john cusack
他/她最喜欢的电影明星
and his/her favorite movie was say anything.
别这样, Ellen
Come on,ellen.
我说, 一盒冰淇淋
I mean,a pint of ice cream,
是不是太老套了?
isn't that a bit cliché?
这是用来装波旁的（一种威士忌酒）
It's for the bourbon.
别绝望
This isn't hopeless.
你会给我找到合适的人的
You're going to find someone for me.
不, 我找不到
No,I won'T.
你会孤独至死
You're going to die alone.
我不会孤独到死
I'm not going to die alone.
看看我
Look at me.
我聪明, 我有吸引力
I'm bright,I'm attractive.
你只要振作起来
You just got to get back out there
继续寻找
and keep looking.
不, 你永远找不到任何人适合你
No,you're never going to find anybody.
每过一年你就老一岁
And every year you're just getting older
这就会变的更加困难
and it's getting harder and harder.
这太可笑了
You're being ridiculous.
不多久我将会出现在这面墙上
I'm going to be up on that wall one of these days.
- 不, 你不会!\n- 不, 我会!
-No,you won't!\n-Yes,I will!
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
我不清楚, 但是我相信
I don't know,but I believe.
如果一只蟑螂和老鼠
Hell,if a cockroach and a mouse
能在这城市找到真爱
can find love in this crazy city,
那么, 他妈的, 我也能
then,damn it,so can I.
你让我迷惑了
You're losing me.
重点是
The point is,
一些好事会发生在我身上
something good's going to happen to me.
也许你的电脑帮的上忙
Maybe your computer will help,
也许不能, 但不管怎样它还是会发生
maybe it won't,but it'll happen.
那我该继续寻找吗?
So I should keep looking?
你当然要
Of course you should.
而且现在, 你会免费为我寻找
And now,you're going to do it for free.